<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-04-19T11:01:47-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title>Benevolent Tech</title><subtitle>A group of friends with technical and emotional depth with an altruistic mission, here to help you catch up to the future.</subtitle><author><name>Benevolent Tech</name><email>hi@benevolent.tech</email></author><entry><title>How to Make Your Site Search Engine Friendly</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/marketing/how-to-make-your-site-search-engine-friendly.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Make Your Site Search Engine Friendly" /><published>2017-04-13T07:10:13-04:00</published><updated>2017-04-13T07:10:13-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/marketing/how-to-make-your-site-search-engine-friendly</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/marketing/how-to-make-your-site-search-engine-friendly.html">&lt;p&gt;In this first of our SEO primer series, we cover the highest impact strategies to attract more people to your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Make your site search engine friendly &amp;lt;– you are here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plan your content&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Write content worth sharing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Encourage sharing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Advertise on a budget&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on how old you are, you might remember the early days of the Internet, which were sometime around the mid to late 1990s. In those days, there was no Google. The main search engines were Yahoo and AOL, and let’s face it, we remember just how user-un-friendly AOL tended to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yahoo, in those days, looked somewhat like Google does now: a bit Spartan in appearance, though with some obvious differences, such as clickable category links (e.g. sports, religion, business, etc) that took you to sub-categories. Once you clicked on the sub-category you wanted, that sub-category took you either to more sub-categories, or to lists of indexed URLs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These were also the early days of Internet browsers, with no tablets or smart phones with horizontal or vertical screen views. Internet Explorer duked it out with Netscape Navigator for popularity and usability, while Safari stayed (as it always has) in the strict “core” of Apple’s user base. And Opera, like it always has, struggled to make itself be noticed like an eternal prom-queen-wannabe who never got elected, let alone had a decent dance with her crush.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feels like ancient history now, doesn’t it? Feels like we’re a mite spoiled here in “the future,” especially now that we have Google, the once-upon-a-time school project, which has become the mother of all search engines. Remember any of the other search engines from the 90s and early 00’s? Neither do we.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, because Google has become this behemoth with its own distinct algorithms that make searching the now equally gigantic world of the “information superhighway” all the easier to navigate, gaining a spot in the first ten search results has turned into an ongoing battle that rivals the competitive force of the Olympic games. Only you’re looking to be the Michael Phelps of the search rankings, and not so much the swimming pool. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in order to help you get to that top spot, or at least help you get to the top page of listings, we’ve put together this SEO primer series of articles. In this series, we cover the highest impact strategies to attract more people to your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;part-1-how-to-make-your-site-search-engine-friendly&quot;&gt;Part 1: How to Make Your Site Search Engine Friendly&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may have a huge fanbase and massive traffic, but ignoring search engine and social network guidelines will sink your online visibility faster than hitting an iceberg on a foggy night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most website platforms support these guidelines, but many of them don’t out of the box. Do your homework and research your options – &lt;a href=&quot;/contact&quot;&gt;or have us do it for you.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the current guidelines to ensuring compatibility:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guideline 1 - Describe your pages with titles, descriptions and a picture&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why? Search engines and social media require this information for search results and sharing. They get really cranky if you don’t have them. In other words, your site won’t get ranked very high, and you won’t get noticed. And trust us, like a gymnast doing a triple-back-flip, you &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to get noticed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guideline 2 - Describe your website’s structure with a sitemap file&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Search engines are imperfect at detecting inner pages of your website. Search engines crawl your page, like hikers on the side of a mountain. If you don’t give them a clear map, they won’t be able to find all the best parts of your site. You can help search engines by having your website platform offer search engines a site-map. It helps Google and other search engines make like spiders and crawl your site that much easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guideline 3 - Use basic network security with https&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve probably noticed that your browser shows an indicator of whether a website is using secure networking next to the current URL. Well, search engines will dock you for not having it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/versions/https---x----400-85x---.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out that search engines kinda care about keeping their users safe (even Yahoo!), go figure? And in these days of identity theft, you might as well have HTTPS for your site. It’s kinda like having an overprotective daddy with not just a shotgun, but a semiautomatic rifle and martial arts skills on top of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guideline 4 - Be kind to all screen sizes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember how we mentioned smartphones and tablets earlier? Also called responsiveness, search engines will dock your search ranking if your website doesn’t look quite right on such modern technology. Yes, we know it sounds sort of petty. But because of the ubiquitousness of smartphones and tablets, it is kind of fair to expect a useable version of your site on them. And let’s face it, by not having a responsive site, you’d be leaving potential sales on the table. If you’re asking “&lt;em&gt;Who does that?&lt;/em&gt;” then you’re on the right track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guideline 5 - Optimize your site’s performance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The amount of time it takes for your web page to load affects perception and satisfaction, so Google docks your search ranking if you load slowly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so we might seem spoiled for loading times anymore, but think about it this way: if you’re old enough, think back to the days of the old 54kbps dial-up modems that sounded like a duck swallowed a kazoo and thought it was a tasty meal. Yeah. You wanted it to go faster. You complained and moaned that Netscape Navigator was as slow as the ships that had the old multi-pronged steering wheel which served as Navigator’s icon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As technology has gotten faster, we’ve become more accustomed to that speed, and we’ve clamored for more. So, it stands to reason that optimized site performance has to stand up to that level of public expectations. We’re pretty sure here that people aren’t about to say “Yes! Please! Take us to the Dark Ages of computers again!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re actually working on a full tips and tricks article on performance – sign up for our email newsletter to get notified when it’s ready!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;andthats-it&quot;&gt;And…that’s it!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you know how to make your site perfect. Actually no you don’t, there are four more steps in this series, But at least it’s a good start.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Benevolent Tech</name><email>hi@benevolent.tech</email></author><summary>In this first of our SEO primer series, we cover the highest impact strategies to attract more people to your site.</summary></entry></feed>
